<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Careers on WISS | Stuttgart Media University</title>
    <link>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Careers on WISS | Stuttgart Media University</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 10:44:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiwi Software und Content Management</title>
      <link>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/hiwi-2016-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 10:44:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/hiwi-2016-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tätigkeiten umfassen u.a.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unterstützung bei den laufenden Forschungsprojekten&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Testen von Open-Source Software zur Verarbeitung von Metadaten&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dokumentation von frei lizenzierten Daten im bibliografischen Bereich&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qualitätssicherung bei automatisch erstellten Metadaten und Analysen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; und was sonst gerade anliegt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Webmaster, insbesondere&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aufbau und Pflege von Webseiten zur Dokumentation der
Forschungsprojekte&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Semantische Annotation der Webseiten&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erste Kenntnisse zur Linux-Konsole und Spaß am Basteln mit Open Source
Programmen und großen Datenmengen sollten vorhanden sein. Alle
weiteren Kenntnisse und Fertigkeiten können im Rahmen der Tätigkeit
erlernt werden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ein Arbeitsplatz an der HdM wird zur Verfügung gestellt - es kann (und
soll teilweise) auch von zuhause gearbeitet werden. Eigenes Notebook
wäre erforderlich (damit die für die Arbeit notwendige Software nicht
an mehreren Rechnern eingerichtet und gepflegt werden muss).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bewerbungen bitte an &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/people/magnus-pfeffer&#34;&gt;Magnus Pfeffer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>career</title>
      <link>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:18:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-8&#34;&gt;
           &lt;h1 id=&#34;industry-partnerships:8abbda204d1f639ee72d70d7bdb257ec&#34;&gt;Industry partnerships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you already have a job and would like to get a doctorate? Or are you looking for a job with this opportunity? Maybe we can help you. Of course, everything about &lt;a href=&#34;get-a-doctorate&#34;&gt;getting a doctorate&lt;/a&gt; applies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the companies to the right, we already have liaisons, be it within research projects, with student employees or mutual research interests. You might want to check if they have interesting offers for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are always interested in new collaborations and exciting new research questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-4&#34;&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry partners:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bosch.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/img/bosch_logo_english.png&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springernature.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/img/logo-springernature.png&#34; style=&#34;padding-top:20px;padding-bottom:20px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.p3-group.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/img/p3_group.png&#34; style=&#34;padding-top: 20px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more on &lt;a href=&#34;industry&#34;&gt;industry partnerships&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>phd</title>
      <link>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/get-a-doctorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:18:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/get-a-doctorate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-8&#34;&gt;
           &lt;h1 id=&#34;get-a-doctorate:02ab76e94bfbdff89a259d0815c127e1&#34;&gt;Get a doctorate&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most project-based positions in our group are targeted at doctoral students, i.e., people with a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree who would like to obtain a doctorate. This is, however, not a strict requirement. Working towards a doctoral degree is a very individual decision and certainly asks for substantial additional research work besides the direct duties of the job offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the dissertation topic and the research project align well so that project results can be used as part of the dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooperation-with-a-university:02ab76e94bfbdff89a259d0815c127e1&#34;&gt;Cooperation with a University&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stuttgart Media University does not issue doctorates. Instead, we cooperate with universities like Humboldt, KIT or Mannheim. This is no disadvantage, as two supervisors are required for a dissertation, anyway. We will help you finding the right university and the right co-supervisor for your research topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like with the decision to pursue a doctorate in general, the choice of supervisors is very individual. The list of universities to the right simply reflects the cooperations we established so far and where we collaborate fruitfully in mutual research projects. If one of these is right for you depends solely on your topic and its fit with the research of your potential co-supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the existing cooperations, we already have a broad variety, from Dr. rer. pol. or Dr.-Ing. at KIT (Computer Science and Business Informatics), Dr. rer. nat. at Mannheim (Computer Science and Business Informatics), Dr. phil. at Humboldt (Information Science) and PhD (Computer Science and Information Science) at UWS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements:02ab76e94bfbdff89a259d0815c127e1&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formal requirements are subject to the requirements of the issuing university. Usually this includes a very good (&amp;lt;= 2.0) master&amp;rsquo;s degree or equivalent in computer science, information science, or a related field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A general requirement is a good command of written and spoken English; research is international and dominated by the English language (there is a reason why this website is only available in English). Don&amp;rsquo;t be too concerned if you think your English is not (yet) good enough, but expect to read and write a lot in English over the next years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming skills are a further requirement. You won&amp;rsquo;t get a degree for your code, but without coding, you won&amp;rsquo;t get your research (and project work) done in computer and information science, at least not in the areas we are interested in (look at the name of this group!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, the main personal requirement is to be organised and self-motivated. It is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; dissertation and you want to get it done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-4&#34;&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cooperating Universities:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uni-mannheim.de&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/img/uni_ma_logo.gif&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kit.edu&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/img/kitlogo.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hu-berlin.de&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/img/hulogo.png&#34; style=&#34;padding-top: 20px;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uws.ac.uk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/img/logo-uws.png&#34; style=&#34;padding-top: 25px; width:150px;x&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiwi JudaicaLink</title>
      <link>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/hiwi-2016-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 10:44:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/career/hiwi-2016-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tätigkeiten umfassen u.a.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weiterentwicklung des Projekts &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.judaicalink.org&#34;&gt;JudaicaLink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration neuer Daten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verbesserung der Crawler für existierende Daten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verlinkung und Anreicherung der Daten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Die Stelle ist an das Projekt &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/projects/fid-judaica&#34;&gt;FID Judaica&lt;/a&gt; angegliedert, das derzeit in der Startphase ist, so dass weitere Entwicklungsaufgaben hinzukommen können.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anforderungen:&lt;/strong&gt;
Selbständige Arbeitsweise, hohe Motivation und Programmierkenntnisse, vorzugsweise Java oder JavaScript, sowie Kenntnisse in HTML. Kenntnisse in Linked Data, Metadaten oder XML von Vorteil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ein Arbeitsplatz an der HdM wird zur Verfügung gestellt - es kann (und
soll teilweise) auch von zuhause gearbeitet werden. Ein eigenes Notebook
ist erforderlich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bewerbungen bitte an &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiss.iuk.hdm-stuttgart.de/people/kai-eckert&#34;&gt;Kai Eckert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>